We’ve looked at empathy, and now we are going to explore Purpose, the second part in the EPIC framework.
Purpose is really about defining what you want to get out of an interaction.
But it’s more than just defining your needs and wants. It’s also taking into consideration the other person’s
needs and wants for the interaction as well.
And so when we look at defining purpose, we want to define it in three ways.
First, we want to explore — given what we understand about how the person is feeling and thinking about the topic —
what is realistically achievable in this meeting or in this interaction?
Second, we want to take into account: what are our goals for this meeting?
And third, we want to look at: what are the other person’s goals for the interaction?
And defining purpose in this
multifaceted way ensures that we are designing or creating an experience or an interaction
that is genuinely inclusive and is a two-way conversation —
that it’s not just about transmitting
your needs, your ideas only in a one-way fashion, but creating a dialogue and building that relationship over the longer term.